ANSUMAN GHOSH

Phone: +919739761446

Mail: ansuman5555@gmail.com

Summary

Backend Developer and QA with 6 years of experience focusing mainly on automation, performance and user experience. Flexible with proven analytical skills and ability to manage multiple projects. Extensive background in Retail domain, Agile/Kanban development methodologies and distributed micro services systems.

Key Skills

- Experienced in Agile/Kanban development methodologies.
- Automate development, test, build and deploy processes.
- Adhere to TDD, BDD, CD, SCM and serverless architecture.
- Actively participate in applications design, data-flows and detailed technical design.
- Provide performance guidelines and recommendations for the backend.
- Deliver rich and high-performance web applications.

Knowledge

Programming languages	Good knowledge: Python, Go, SQL, VBScript, HTML, CSS. Medium knowledge: C, JavaScript/Node.js. Others: Java.
Software/tools	Git, Jira, MySQL, Django, Flask, Chalice, AWS, QTP/UFT, Selenium
Operating systems	Linux, OS X, Windows
Others	Agile/Kanban development, continuous integration & deployment, Test Driven Development and Behaviour Driven Development.

Work Experience

Total experience of 5 years and 10 months in TCS, Client - J Sainsbury plc

Backend Developer (London, Bangalore)

Mar 2014 - Present

- Knowledge of CD/CI setup in amazon AWS.
- Experienced in AWS serverless deployment like API gateway & Lambda.
- Developed backend in Django.
- Developed REST APIs using Flask and Chalice (for AWS lambda).
- Development of automation scripts in Robot Framework for Frontend, Database and API.
- Working experience in TDD & BDD process.
- Working in scrum team as Python Engineer.

Automation Engineer (Bangalore)

May 2013 - Feb 2014

- Feasibility analysis of a Java/Oracle Form based application in QTP
- Development of Automation test script in QTP
- Debugging and maintenance of the developed scripts

Functional Tester (Bangalore)

Sep 2012 - Apr 2013

- Writing Test Scenarios and Test cases as a team member.
- Execution of test cases manually and by automation in QTP & Selenium.
- Debugging of automation scripts for maintenance.

Achievements

- Developed a QTP based hybrid framework with reusable functions.
- Developed Excel Macro which can update the status and defect id of test scripts in HP ALM.
- Developed a web application in Django Framework for the client and appreciated from client.

Certifications

TitleAcquired OnExpires OnISTQB - Foundation Level31/01/2015NA

Education

Qualification	Subject	Board/University	Percentage/Grade
Bachelor of Technology	Electrical Engineering	West Bengal University of Technology	7.5
Standard XII / Higher Secondary	Others	West Bengal Council of Higher Secondary Education	65.28
Standard X / Secondary	Others	West Bengal Board of Secondary Education	68.44